Finding Aid of the UW-Milwaukee Student Union Collection, 1948-2015
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
- Records, 1948-2015, UWM Archival Collection 124; 21.5 cubic ft. (57 boxes) 1 oversize folder 118 digital image files (57 MB) 32 digital video files (18.5 GB)
  - 5. Distinguished Lecture Series Files, 1982-2007
    - 1995
      - West, Cornel
        - Race Matters (Box 39, Folder 11)
        - Video, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 52, Video 9)
    - 1996
      - Adams and Rieder
        - A Quest for Common Ground (Box 40, Folder 1)
        - Video, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 52, Video 13)
      - Alberts, Bruce Michael (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Wu, Harry
        - Program (Box 40, Folder 3)
        - Video, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 52, Video 14)
    - 1997
      - Fallows, James
        - Program (Box 40, Folder 4)
        - Video, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 53, Video 1)
      - Butler, Robert (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - 1998
      - Guerrilla Girls (Box 40, Folder 6)
      - Waring, Marilyn (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - 1999
      - Davis, Angela
        - Program (Box 40, Folder 8)
        - Video, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 53, Video 7)
      - Davis/Koethe Photographs (Box 49, Folder 16)
      - Koethe, John (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - 2001
      - Smith, Anna Deavere
        - Program (Box 40, Folder 10)
        - Video, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 53, Video 8)
      - Walker, Alice, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 53, Video 9)
    - 2002
      - Leakey, Richard, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 53, Video 12)
      - Malouf, David, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 53, Video 2)
      - West, Cornel
        - Program (Box 40, Folder 11)
        - Photographs (Box 49, Folder 17)
        - Video, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 54, Video 4)
    - 2003
      - Guillermoprieto, Alma, Columbia: The Unbroken War, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 54, Video 12)
      - Mosley, Walter
        - Legacy of Amadou Diallo, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 55, Video 5)
        - What Next, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 54, Video 13)
      - Schlosser, Eric, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 54, Video 9)
      - Totenberg, Nina, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 54, Video 10)
    - 2004
      - Olmos, Edward James, 2004, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 55, Video 7)
      - West, Cornel, 2004, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 54, Video 14)
    - 2005
      - Kushner, Tony, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 55, Video 11)
      - Spiegelman, Art, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 56, Video 1)
      - Wolf, Naomi
        - Program (Box 40, Folder 12)
        - Video, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 56, Video 9)
    - 2006
      - Giovanni, Nikki, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 56, Video 5)
      - Wild, David, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 56, Video 11)
    - 2007
      - Goodman, Amy, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 56, Video 12)
      - Kennedy, Robert F. Jr., Videocassette (VHS) (Box 56, Video 6)
      - Rodriguez, Julie Chavez, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 56, Video 14)
      - Scheck, Barry, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 56, Video 10)
    - 2011
      - McMillan, Terry
    - Undated
      - Malcolm X Rendition (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - 6. Union Cinema Files, 1978-2015
    - Programming
      - Cinema
        - 1978-1985 (Box 41, Folder 1-7)
        - 1985-1991 (Box 42, Folder 1-3)
      - Theater
        - 1992-2008 (Box 42, Folder 4-11)
        - 2008-2009 (Box 43, Folder 1-2)
    - Specific Programs
      - Asian Film Festival, 2001-2009 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Festival of Films in French, 2002-2008 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Latin American Film Series, 1993-2008 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Latin American Film Series, Poster, 1986 (Oversize 1)
      - Milwaukee LGBT Film/Video Festival, 1983-2015
        The first annual gay and lesbian film festival in Milwaukee was organized by the Lavender Commitment student organization at the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee in January 1983. It wasn't the first time that gay and lesbian films were shown at UWM--the Gay Peoples Union student organization had screened films in the Union in 1971, and the Gay & Lesbian Community organization had shown films in 1982 as part of UWM's Gay Day--but 1983 was the first time that screenings were billed as an annual event. The Lavender Commitment held six annual festivals from 1983 to 1988. In 1992 Great Lakes Film & Video (GLFV), with significant financial support from the Cream City Foundation, began its own LGBT film and video series. This series ran until 1996, in which year there was both a spring and fall festival. In 1996, GLFV became a programming arm of UWM's School of Fine Arts, where the festival currently resides.
        This series includes promotional materials of the Milwaukee LGBT Film/Video Festival, as well as its precedecessors, the Lavender Commitment student organization from 1983 through 1988 and Great Lakes Film & Video Festival from 1992 through 1996.
        Further information about the Lavender Commitment student organization may be found in the UW-Milwaukee Office of the Dean of Student Records (
        UWM Archival Collection 48
        ), and information about the Great Lakes Film & Video Festival in the Cream City Foundation Records (
        UWM Manuscript Collection 205
        ). Researchers should also consult Union Theatre programming materials elsewhere in this collection.
        - General Promotional Materials, 1983-2015 (Box 43, Folder 6-15)
        - Posters/Programs (Oversized), 1983-1996, 2006-2008, 2014-2015 (Box 6)
      - Soviet Women in Film, Poster, 1988 (Oversize 1)
      - Women Without Borders Film Series, 2005-2008 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - 7. Gasthaus Entertainment Series Files, 2001-2005
    - Gasthaus Entertainment Series, 2001-2005 (Box 44, Folder 1-9)
  - 8. Publications, 1963-2009
    - Bookstore
      - Calendars
        - 1963-1992 (Box 44, Folder 10-12)
        - 1993-2009 (Box 45, Folder 1-3)
      - Newsletter, 1979-2006 (Box 45, Folder 4-6)
    - Campus Building Magazine, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Craft Centre Brochures, 2003-2008 (Box 45, Folder 8-12)
    - Preview: A Complete Guide to the UWM Union, 1979-1984 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Preview: A Calendar of Events
      - 1982-1983 (Box 45, Folder 15)
      - 1984-2009 (Box 46, Folder 1-8)
    - Preview: This Month in the UWM Union, 1979-1981 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Satelite: A Bilingual Variety Newspaper, 1984 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Union Information/History Booklets, 1991 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Union News, 1964-1978 (Box 47, Folder 3-5)
    - Union Newsletters, 2003-2004 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - UWM Campus Guide, 2000 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Women's Resource Center Newsletter, 1994-1996 (Box 47, Folder 8)
- Event Files and Photographs, 1981-2015, Accession 2015-008; 5.2 cubic feet (6 boxes) 455 digital files (2 GB); Photographs and publicity materials for events held in the Student Union. Most of the content is from the programming departments in the union, in particular Sociocultural Programming, the Union Theater, and the Union Art Gallery. In many cases the photographs correspond to events in the existing collection; the photos are internal to the Union and not duplicative of material in Photo Services. The electronic files also include annual reports for the Union and its constituent departments from 2008-2015, as well as digital images of events in the Student Arts and Crafts Center and Union Art Gallery.
  - African Americans in Education Conference, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports, 2007-2014
  - Art Gallery Images
    - Bound and Beyond, 2014
    - Crossing Over, 2014
    - Dia de los Muertos, 2015
    - Dwelling, 2014
    - Identity Check, 2015
    - Interface, 2015
    - Visualizing Sovereignty, 2015
  - Artist Fair, 2015
  - Board of Regents Reception Videos, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Campus Activities, 2008 (Box 1)
  - CaribbeanFest, 2010 (Box 1)
  - Cinco de Mayo, 2010-2011 (Box 1)
  - The Dangerous Game, 2014
  - Director Awards Presentation, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Earth Week, 2015
  - Events, 2001-2002 (Box 1)
  - Film
    - African American Film Festival, 2009-2011 (Box 1)
    - Cinema, 1983-1988 (Box 1)
    - Gay and Lesbian Film Festival, 1994-1998 (Box 1)
    - Programming, 1994-1998 (Box 1)
  - Food Services Events, 1982-1984 (Box 1)
  - Food Services Events, 1983-1985 (Box 2)
  - Geek Week, 2015
  - Get Ready for Mardi Gras, 2015
  - Henna, 2014
  - Jane Goodall, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Junot Diaz, 2011 (Box 2)
  - Marketing, 2010-2011 (Box 2)
  - Maya Angelou, 2000 (Box 2)
  - The Meeting, 2000 (Box 2)
  - New Muslim Cool, 2010 (Box 2)
  - Open Clay, 2014
  - Photographs
    - Activities, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - Art Gallery Shows, 1983-1986 (Box 5)
    - Artwork, 1980-1995 (Box 5)
    - Campus Photos, 1980-1989 (Box 6)
    - Event Photos, 1981-1989 (Box 6)
    - Irish Fest and Other Events, 1984-1986 (Box 6)
    - Polaroids, 1981-1984 (Box 6)
    - Slides, 1981-1988 (Box 6)
  - Popcorn Forum, 2010 (Box 2)
  - Programming, 2002, 2009 (Box 2)
  - Programming and Associated Departments Annual Reports, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Recreation Center, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Self-Studies, 1982-1984 (Box 2)
  - Sociocultural Programming, 1988-1990 (Box 2)
  - Sociocultural Programming, 1990-2009 (Box 3)
  - Stacyann Chin, 2009 (Box 3)
  - Student Affairs, 1986-1990 (Box 3)
  - Student Arts and Crafts Center Reports, 2014-2015
  - Student Organizations, 2010
  - Taste of Africa, 2011 (Box 3)
  - Terrarium Event, 2015
  - Theater Calendar, 2014-2015
  - Tie Dye Event, 2014
  - Unclothed, 2008 (Box 3)
  - Union Theater, 1994-2001 (Box 4)
  - Upeople Project, 2011 (Box 3)
  - Yearbooks and Reports, 1980-2004 (Box 3)